

Matthew Clifford (TechIOSH)

Health & Safety Technical Advisor, Trainer and Auditor

Email: matthewclifford@hotmail.co.uk

Tel: +44 7708 913 089 **Address:** Hertfordshire, UK

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-clifford-21aa9511/

Matthew has a solid and detailed background in H&S auditing as well as researching and delivering technical advice and training in a number of specialist areas of the travel and hospitality industries, such as accommodations and excursions. Matthew also has both shop floor and management level experience in customer services and business management. Having worked throughout the world, including Europe, USA, South Africa, Thailand, North Africa and 3 years working and living in Madrid, Spain, Matthew has gained a wealth of experience and ability in his chosen sector of H&S and Statutory Compliance for the travel sector.

Furthermore, Matthew is also experienced in web-development, with extensive knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP, as well as a decent understanding of SQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

H&S TECHNICAL ADVISOR, TRAINER AND AUDITOR

Checkpoint Solutions

UK: August 2007 to September 2009 - July 2014 to July 2016 - May 2019 to May 2020

- Auditing Execution of fire safety, food hygiene and general safety audits within accommodations, excursions and land transportations across the globe.
- Training Creation and provision of training courses within the H&S field, including classroom training, webinars, online training and shadow auditing.
- Technical Guidance documents related to technical aspects of H&S within accommodations, excursions and land transportations.

H&S TECHNICAL ADVISOR, TRAINER AND AUDITOR

SGS Madrid

Spain: July 2016 - March 2019

- Training Creation and provision of training courses within the H&S field, including classroom training, webinars, online training and shadow auditing.
- Technical Guidance documents related to technical aspects of H&S within accommodations, excursions and land transportations.
- Auditing Execution of fire safety, food hygiene and general safety audits within accommodations, excursions and land transportations.
- Hands-on support to the planning, validation, follow-up and incident monitoring teams.

CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER

OPRO Itd

UK: April 2011 - March 2014 and May 2014 - July 2014

 Customer Service Manager - Overseeing all aspects of the company's customer service department including queries and complaints via switchboard and emails, to managing a team of 6 staff within the department.

MANAGEMENT ASSISTANT

Enterprise-Rent-A-Car

UK: April 2010 - April 2011

Management Assistant - Customer Service, Finance, Marketing, Fleet Management and Sales.

CERTIFICATES

- NEBOSH General Certificate
- Principles of Fire Safety
- COVID-19: Infection Prevention & PPE
- Level 3 Award in Supervising Food Safety in Catering
- Auditor Training School Travel Forum
- Travel-life Sustainability in Tourism
- Legionella and Legionnaires Disease Awareness

LANGUAGES





EDUCATION

Music Production - BA(Hons) University of Greenwich Canterbury, UK 09/2004 - 12/2007

- Music Production BA(Hons)
- Music Production (HND)